Guide to the Henry Horenstein photographs, 1970-2013 RL.11564
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Henry Horenstein photographs
1970-2013
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
Horenstein, Henry
RL.11564
7.0 Linear Feet 9 boxes 153 prints
Collection comprises 153 black-and-white and color prints selected from projects by photographer Henry Horenstein. Subjects in this collection range widely: appearing in the images are members of Horenstein's family; beachgoers in Cuba; blues and country musicians and their fans; the human body seen in extreme close-ups; racing jockeys, horses, and gamblers; burlesque and drag performers; and street scenes, storefronts, theaters, highways, and nightlife in various places. Locations include Havana, Los Angeles, Louisiana, Maryland, Massachusetts, Missouri, New York, Tennessee, Texas, and Venezuela. "Wesorts" refers to unique mixed-race communities in central Maryland whose residents refer to themselves as "we sorts." Formats include chromogenic, pigment inkjet (giclee), and gelatin silver prints, in sizes ranging from 8x10 to 20x24 inches. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Arrangement
The prints are organized by bodies of work, in alphabetical order: Branson; Close Relations; Cuba; Honky Tonk; Humans; Louisiana; Margins; Racing Days; Shoot What You Love; Show; and Wesorts.
Content Description
Collection comprises 153 black-and-white and color prints from portfolios by photographer Henry Horenstein, taken from 1970 to 2013 over the course of his long career. Subjects range widely, with some emphasis in the collection on images of entertainment and music culture: country and blues musicians, including Nathan Abshire, Loretta Lynn, Del McCoury, Dolly Parton, Stringbean, and Doc Watson, the venues where they perform, and their fans; street musicians, honky tonk bands and barroom dancers and drinkers; and drag and burlesque performers in Los Angeles, New York City, and Caracas and Buenos Aires, Venezuela.
"Wesorts" refers to a project to document small, unique mixed-race communities in and near Marbury, Maryland; the term is said to have been coined from the phrase used by residents to refer to themselves, "we sorts of people."
Other images include early portraits of Horenstein's family and friends; life on the El Malecón waterfront in Havana, Cuba; a highway in Louisiana; a historic theater in Branson, Missouri; close-up images of the human body; and behind the scenes in horse racing, including horses in action and at rest, grooms, owners, bettors, and jockeys, one of whom is Steve Cauthen.
The prints come in sizes ranging from roughly 8x10 to 20x24 inches. Photographic formats include chromogenic, pigment inkjet (giclee), and gelatin silver darkroom prints; they are often marked with edition numbers, printing dates, and other information.
With only a few exceptions, the images in this collection have been published by Horenstein in photobooks throughout his career. They have been exhibited widely and are held in the collections of museums, galleries, and other institutions.
Biographical / Historical
American-born photographer, documentary filmmaker, author, and teacher based in Boston, Henry Horenstein is noted for his portraiture and documentary projects on a wide variety of subjects. Horenstein studied history at the University of Chicago and received a BFA and MFA at Rhode Island School of Design (RISD), where he is currently professor of photography. He studied photography with Harry Callahan, Aaron Siskind, Minor White, and others. His work has been widely exhibited at the Smithsonian, J. Paul Getty Museum, High Museum of Art, San Francisco Museum of Modern Art, Philadelphia Museum of Art, Museum of Fine Arts, Houston, and published in photobooks, including Close Relations (2006); Racing Days (1987); Humans (2004); Honky Tonk: Portraits of Country Music (2012); Shoot What You Love (2016); and Show (2010).
From the artist's own statement about his work:
"Over the years I've photographed many different types of subjects, even animals and the human form. But I've always returned to my roots as a documentary photographer. More than anything, I like a good story. And I try to tell one in a direct way, with humor and a punch line, if possible. With this in mind, I have photographed country musicians in Nashville, my family and friends in Massachusetts, horse racing at Saratoga, nightlife in Buenos Aires, old highways everywhere, everyone in Cajun Louisiana, South American baseball, camel breeding in Dubai, tri-racial families in Maryland, and much, much more."
"For subjects, I prefer older cultures and places, especially disappearing ones. That's what my history teachers, Jesse Lemisch (at University of Chicago) and E.P. Thompson (at University of Warwick), taught me to do. These cultures and places might vanish, but it is a historian's righteous duty to make sure that they leave a trace. I also was very influenced by another teacher in Chicago, John G. Cawelti, who taught me (and doubting historians predating him) that popular culture should be taken seriously. One other great influence for me was my teacher at Rhode Island School of Design, Harry Callahan. Harry encouraged me to 'shoot what you love,' and to pay no attention to what others are doing. 'Even if you make bad pictures,' he said, 'you'll have a good time.' Thank you for that, Harry."
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Henry Horenstein photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift from 2017-2020.
Bluegrass musicians -- Photographs; Burlesque shows -- Photographs; Country musicians -- Photographs; Dancers -- Portraits; Drag shows -- Photographs; Families -- United States -- Photographs; Female impersonators -- Portraits; Honky-tonk musicians -- Photographs; Horse racing -- Photographs; Jockeys -- United States -- Photographs; Musicians -- Portraits; Photographers -- Massachusetts; Racially mixed people -- Maryland -- Photographs; Roadhouses -- Photographs; Havana (Cuba) -- Photographs; Louisiana -- Photographs; Maryland -- Photographs; United States -- Social life and customs -- 20th century; Venezuela -- Photographs; Black-and-white photographs; Chromogenic color prints; Digital prints; Gelatin silver prints; Inkjet prints; Pigment prints; Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University); Horenstein, Henry
- Branson, 1995, 1997; 2 prints
  Scope and Contents
  These color images were taken in the historic Sons of the Pioneers Theater in Branson, Missouri. They were both published in Branson and Shoot What You Love. The prints measure approximately 16x20 inches.
  - John, Elvis, Marilyn, Charlie, Branson, Missouri, 1995; 16 x 19 7/8 inches; Chromogenic print (Box 1, Image RL.11564-P-0001)
    Color print Image of a mural of celebrities at the Sons of the Pioneers historic theater in Branson, Missouri.
  - Sons of the Pioneers Theater, Branson, Missouri, 1997; 16 x 20 inches; Chromogenic print (Box 1, Image RL.11564-P-0002)
    Image is of a hat and trumpet still life.
- Close Relations, 1970-1976; 1.5 Linear Feet 28 prints 16x20 inches
  This series of early work by photographer Henry Horenstein consists of black-and-white and a few color portraits of Horenstein's friends, family members and their friends, a family poodle, and a few other various individuals. Most are interior shots taken in kitchens, bedrooms, and other settings, but a handful were taken outdoors. One image is of a room with no people present. The images were almost all taken in Massachusetts, with the exception of one taken in North Carolina; two are in unknown locations. All prints measure approximately 16x20 inches; most were printed in 2019 and 2020.
  These images have been published in the photobook Close Relations, and several appear in Shoot What You Love and Histories.
  - Dennis and Mary, our apartment, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1971; 16 x 19 7/8 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 1, Image RL.11564-P-0003)
  - Chammie, my parent's bedroom, Newton, Massachusetts, 1974; 16 x 20 inches; Chromogenic print (Box 1, Image RL.11564-P-0004)
  - Dad and Mom, golf course, Brookline, Massachusetts, 1972; 16 x 19 7/8 inches; Chromogenic print (Box 1, Image RL.11564-P-0005)
  - Susan, Boston, Massachusetts, 1970; 19 3/4 x 15 3/4 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0081)
    Marks: 12/19; LN #9-9
    Edition: 1 of 7
  - Carrie, Mattapan, Massachusetts, 1975; 19 3/4 x 15 7/8 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0082)
    Marks: 12/19; LN #440-2
    Edition: 1 of 6
  - Friend of Barbara's, kitchen, New Bedford, Massachusetts, 1971; 19 3/4 x 15 7/8 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0083)
    Marks: 11/19; LN #35-10
    Edition: 1 of 5
  - Guests, charity party, Newton, Massachusetts, 1972; 19 3/4 x 15 3/4 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0084)
    Marks: Vintage Print; #251-10
  - Elaine and Brian. Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1971; 19 3/4 x 15 3/4 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0085)
    Marks: 11/19; LN #42-8
    Edition: 1 of 8
  - Foyer, Newton, Massachusetts, 1971; 15 7/8 x 19 3/4 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0086)
    Marks: 11/19; NN #52-4
  - Frances, Jamaica Plain, Massachusetts, 1971; 15 7/8 x 19 3/4 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0087)
    Marks: 11/19; LN #78-3
  - Frances, Jamaica Plain, Massachusetts, 1971; 15 3/4 x 19 3/4 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0088)
    Marks: 11/19; LN #78a-10. The negative number on the inventory sheet is given as 71_97-7.
    Edition: 1 of 10
  - Christine, Boston, Massachusetts, 1972; 15 3/4 x 19 3/4 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0089)
    Marks: Apr. 1972; No.190 #4
    Edition: 1 of 2
  - Chammie, backyard, Newton, Massachusetts, 1972; 19 3/4 x 15 7/8 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0090)
    Marks: 12/19; LN #194-5
  - Guests, charity party, Newton, Massachusetts, 1972; 19 7/8 x 15 7/8 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0091)
    Marks: 11/19; LN #252-7
  - Chammie and Uncle George, Newton, Massachusetts, 1973; 15 7/8 x 19 3/4 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0092)
    Marks: 11/19; LN #330-8
  - Susan Sheridan, Boston, Massachusetts, 1973; 19 3/4 x 15 7/8 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0093)
    Marks: 11/19; LN #352-7
  - Brendan, Charlestown, Massachusetts, 1973; 19 3/4 x 15 3/4 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0094)
    Marks: 12/19; LN #479-11
  - Mom, Chammie, and Dad, backyard, Newton, Massachusetts, 1970; 15 7/8 x 19 3/4 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0095)
    Marks: 11/19; #24-10
  - Mom, Chammie, and Studley, kitchen, Newton, Massachusetts, 1971; 19 3/4 x 15 7/8 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0096)
    Marks: 71.68(7); 8-20-09; AMM; 2/4
    Edition: 1 of 1
  - Newton High School 25 Year Reunion, Chestnut Hill, Massachusetts, 1973; 19 3/4 x 15 3/4 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0097)
    Marks: 12/19; LN #316-7
  - Emily Williams, 1976; 19 3/4 x 15 3/4 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0098)
    Marks: 12/19; LN #481-7
  - Jan, Fresh Pond, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1971; 15 7/8 x 19 3/4 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0099)
    Marks: 11/19; LN #49-10
    Edition: 1 of 4
  - Bert, Everett, Massachusetts, 1971; 19 3/4 x 15 7/8 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0100)
    Marks: 12/19; LN 130-10
  - Sally Stein, 1973; 19 3/4 x 15 7/8 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0101)
    Marks: 11/19; LN #311-5
  - David Akiba, Boston, Massachusetts, 1972; 15 7/8 x 19 3/4 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0102)
    Marks: 11/19; LN #292-4
  - Hadasah luncheon, New Bedford, Massachusetts, 1973; 15 7/8 x 19 3/4 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0103)
    Marks: 11/19; LN #313-10
  - Hadasah luncheon organizer, New Bedford, Massachusetts, 1973; 19 3/4 x 15 7/8 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0104)
    Marks: 11/19; LN #313-12
  - Margaret, North Carolina, 1973; 15 7/8 x 19 3/4 inches (Box 7, Image RL.11564-P-0105)
    Marks: LN 11/19; #325-7
- Cuba (El Malecón, Havana), 2000; .5 Linear Feet 1 box 15 photographic prints 8x12 inches
  These 15 black-and-white photographs were shot by Henry Horenstein in winter of 2000 at a beach area called "The Malecón" in Havana, Cuba. They are almost all portraits of men and boys spending recreational time at this waterfront area. The prints measure approximately 8x12 inches and are in the original order as received from the photographer. They were all printed in 2019.
  Horenstein comments on this portfolio:
  "The Malecón is like a park for the people of Havana. Since it was the holidays [when I went], a lot of kids were out there during the day, swimming or boxing across the street. Families would come after work and have a picnic dinner. At around nine or ten in the evening, young people would come out to party and by one in the morning, it was a very sketchy crowd. I would occasionally be approached for 'extra activities.'...
  "I spent the whole time in the Malecón and really enjoyed myself. People were super friendly. No one had a problem being photographed. They could use a model fee, which was like 50 cents or a dollar. I chose to shoot in black and white because so many people were shooting the houses and cars of Cuba in colour then. I put the photographs away for a long time. I didn't want to be another invading photographer. I just wanted to make classic documentary-style photographs."
  [Source: anothermanmag.com, accessed March 17, 2020]
  - Boy on basketball court, Malecón, Havana, Cuba, 2000; 8x12 inches (Box 8, Image RL.11564-P-0106)
    Marks: 00-351 #10
  - Three boys, Malecón, Havana, Cuba, 2000; 12x8 inches (Box 8, Image RL.11564-P-0107)
    Marks: 00-323 #9
  - Boy smiling, Malecón, Havana, Cuba, 2000; 8x12inches (Box 8, Image RL.11564-P-0108)
    Marks: 00-330 #24
  - Boy with soccer ball, Malecón, Havana, Cuba, 2000; 8x12 inches (Box 8, Image RL.11564-P-0109)
    Marks: 00-361 #22; 1/15
  - Boy's sandals, Malecón, Havana, Cuba, 2000; 8X12 inches (Box 8, Image RL.11564-P-0110)
    Negative number: 00_360-35
  - Boy's shadowed chest, Malecón, Havana, Cuba, 2000; 8X12 inches (Box 8, Image RL.11564-P-0111)
    Negative number: 00_324-22
  - Boys with dogs, Malecón, Havana, Cuba, 2000; 12x8 inches (Box 8, Image RL.11564-P-0112)
    Marks: 00-360 #9
  - Fan of Elian's, Malecón, Havana, Cuba, 2000; 8X12 inches (Box 8, Image RL.11564-P-0113)
    Marks: 00-382 #5
  - Girls on the wall, Malecón, Havana, Cuba, 2000; 8X12 inches (Box 8, Image RL.11564-P-0114)
    Negative number: 00_327-20
  - Kids by the water, Malecón, Havana, Cuba, 2000; 8X12 inches (Box 8, Image RL.11564-P-0115)
    Negative number: 00_353-4
  - Kids watching boxing match, Malecón, Havana, Cuba, 2000; 8X12 inches (Box 8, Image RL.11564-P-0116)
    Negative number: 00_373-32
  - Looking out, Malecón, Havana, Cuba, 2000; 12x8 inches (Box 8, Image RL.11564-P-0117)
    Negative number: 00_348-35
  - Man on edge, Malecón, Havana, Cuba, 2000; 12x8 inches (Box 8, Image RL.11564-P-0118)
    Marks: 00-333 #3; 1/15
  - Man smoking, Malecón, Havana, Cuba, 2000; 12x8 inches (Box 8, Image RL.11564-P-0119)
    Marks: 00-382 #33
  - Man turned, Malecón, Havana, Cuba, 2000; 12x8 inches (Box 8, Image RL.11564-P-0120)
    Marks: 00-350 #1; 1/15
- Honky Tonk, 1972-2013 and undated; .5 Linear Feet 1 box 31 prints 16 x 20 inches
  These black-and-white photographs were taken as part of a long-term project by Horenstein to document traditional American music culture through images of performers and the local bars, music halls, theaters, and music festivals they frequent, as well as images of the music fans, lovers, drinkers, servers, and dancers who inhabit these venues. A few images of musicians were taken at their homes. Featured performers include Nathan Abshire, Waylon Jennings, Loretta Lynn, Del McCoury, Charlie Monroe, Dolly Parton, Hank Snow, Stringbean, Doc Watson, among others. Venues range from the Gettysburg, Pennsylvania Bluegrass Festival, to the Grand Ole Opry, to Tootsie's Orchid Lounge in Tennessee and the Take It Easy Ranch in Maryland. One image is of an unidentified elderly African American street musician in Houston, Texas.
  The images have been published in the photobook Honky Tonk; some also are featured in Shoot What You Love.
  Prints are arranged in chronological order and are sized approximately 16 x 20 inches.
  - Dancing to Webb Pierce, Lone Star Ranch, Reeds Ferry, New Hampshire, 1972; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0026)
    Marks: Vintage.
  - Don Stover, Billerica, Massachusetts, 1972; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0027)
    Edition: 5 of 25; MFK 2012.
  - Jukebox, Tootsie's Orchid Lounge, Nashville, Tennessee, 1972; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0028)
    Edition: 4 of 25. Marks: 297 #3; 1972.
  - Leaving the Opry, Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, Tennessee, 1972; 16 x 20 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0029)
    Marks: 55 #4; 1974.
  - Maurice Lipscomb with his dog, First Church Congregational, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1972; 16 x 19 3/4 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0006)
    Marks: No. 293, #12
  - Stringbean, Grand Ole Opry, Nashville, Tennessee, 1972; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0030)
  - Waiting backstage, Grand Ole Opry, Nashville, Tennessee, 1972; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0031)
    Edition: 6 of 25.
  - Charlie Monroe, Take It Easy Ranch, Callaway, Maryland, 1973; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0032)
    Marks: 326 #4; 1973.
  - Blue Sky Boys, Gettysburg Bluegrass Festival, Gettysburg, Pennsylvania, 1974; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0033)
    Marks: 321 #3; 1974.
  - Curly Ray Cline, Rock House, Kentucky, 1974; 16 x 20 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0034)
    Marks: 414 #11.
  - Del McCoury, Gettysburg Bluegrass Festival, Gettysburg, Pennsylvania, 1974; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0035)
    Edition: 6 of 25. Marks: 377 #2; 1974.
  - Doc Watson, Performance Center, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1974; 19 7/8 x 15 7/8 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0007)
    Edition: 7 of 25. Marks: 388
  - Dolly Parton, Boston Symphony Hall, Boston, Massachusetts, 1974; 19 7/8 x 15 7/8 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0008)
    Edition: 15 of 25. Marks: 288 / #7 / AMC 11 '07
  - Hank Snow, Grand Ole Opry, Nashville, Tennessee, 1974; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0036)
    Marks: 349 #8; 1974. Original mylar envelope is marked with estimated print date "2000s."
  - Harmonica player, Merchant's Cafe, Nashville, Tennessee, 1974; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0037)
    Edition: 1 of 3. Marks: 435 #10; 1975.
  - Last call, Tootsie's Orchid Lounge, Nashville, Tennessee, 1974; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0038)
    Marks: MK 2012.
  - Playing for tips, Tootsie's Orchid Lounge, Nashville, Tennessee, 1974; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0039)
    Edition: 4 of 25. Marks: 431 #7; 1975 / 2003.
  - Ponderosa, near Pikesville, Kentucky, 1974; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0040)
    Edition: 3 of 25. Marks: 1974 / 2012, MK 2012.
  - Waiting in line (2), Grand Ole Opry, Nashville, Tennessee, 1974; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0041)
  - House band jam, Tootsie's Orchid Lounge, Nashville, Tennessee, 1975; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0042)
    Marks: 432.
  - Loretta Lynn, Annapolis, Maryland, 1975; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0043)
    Edition: 1 of 25. Marks: 329 #5; 1973.
  - Playground, Lone Star Ranch, Reeds Ferry, New Hampshire, 1975; 16 x 20 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0044)
    Edition: 3 of 25. Marks: 85 #18; 1975; 6B 103.
  - Waylon Jennings, Performance Center, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1976; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0045)
    Edition: AP 1 of 3. Marks: 450 #2. 1975 / 2003. Image size: 15x15 inches.
  - Beer drinker, Kingfish Lounge, Baton Rouge, Louisiana, 1977; 16 x 19 7/8 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0010)
    Marks: No. 132 #27 / HH58 Aug. 1977 / and camera settings
  - Nathan Abshire, Basile, Louisiana, 1977; 16 x 20 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0046)
  - Country comedy, The Baldknobbers Theater, Branson, Missouri, 1995; 20 x 16 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0047)
    Marks: 95-200; vintage (on sleeve).
  - Ferlin Husky ending his show, Branson, Missouri, 1996; 16 x 20 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0048)
    Marks: 97-080; vintage.
  - Street singer, downtown Houston, Texas, 2008; 15 7/8 x 19 7/8 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0009)
    Marks: #4
  - Preacher Jack, Tavern at the End of the World, Somerville, Massachusetts, 2009; 16 x 20 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0049)
  - Early bird, Trout's Bakersfield, California, 2013; 16 x 20 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0050)
  - Retired country music fan, Lone Star Ranch, undated, 16 x 20 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0051)
    Marks: vintage (on sleeve).
- Humans, 2003; 3 prints
  Images are selected from a 2003 project to photograph features of the human body from a very close-up, intimate perspective. All were published in Horenstein's photobook, Humans.
  - Untitled, Plate #10 (breast, side view), 2003; 19 7/8 x 15 7/8 inches; Gelatin silver print, sepia toned (Box 1, Image RL.11564-P-0011)
    Edition: 1 of 25. Marks: 04-103 #24 / GH 13
  - Untitled, Plate #11 (profile of face), 2003; 19 7/8 x 15 7/8 inches; Gelatin silver print, sepia toned (Box 1, Image RL.11564-P-0012)
    Edition: 2 of 25
  - Untitled, Plate #45 (arms lifted, torso from side), 2003; 19 3/4 x 15 7/8 inches; Gelatin silver print, sepia toned (Box 1, Image RL.11564-P-0013)
    Edition: 3 of 25. Marks: 03-575 #7-A
- Louisiana, 2008
  This print was published in the photobook Shoot What You Love.
  - Abandoned car, Highway 1, Marksville, Louisiana, 2008; 16 x 19 7/8 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 1, Image RL.11564-P-0014)
- Margins, 1997, 2009; 2 prints
  The image of Falcone was published in Shoot What You Love.
  - Fire eater, County Fair, Rt. 9, Ballston Spa, New York, 1997; 19 7/8 x 15 7/8 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 1, Image RL.11564-P-0015)
    Marks: 97.216 (17-A) / 9-16-09 AMM 4/4
  - Blitto Falcone, Buenos Aires, Venezuela, 2009; 16 x 19 7/8 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 1, Image RL.11564-P-0016)
- Racing Days, 1975-1994; 1.5 Linear Feet 3 boxes 31 prints
  These black-and-white images form part of a project documenting the culture and surroundings of horse racing in New York State, Maryland, and other localities. Visiting race tracks and associated buildings and interiors, Hornstein captures horses in action and at rest, jockeys, grooms, betters, and racing fans. Portraits of two notable jockeys appear: Steve Cauthen, and one of the few women jockeys, Joey Rusham. The images have been published in Horenstein's photobook Racing Days; several also appear in Histories and in Shoot What You Love.
  Prints are arranged in chronological order and are housed according to sheet sizes, ranging from approximately 8x10 to 20x24 inches.
  - Saddling trees, Saratoga Race Course, 1975; 16 1/2 x 23 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 4, Image RL.11564-P-0052)
    Edition: 4 of 4. Marks: 94-15.
  - Groom and horse, Linzay Downs Racetrack, Opelousas, Louisiana, 1977; 11 x 14 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 5, Image RL.11564-P-0053)